Donell Carter Fortmill, SC

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Reliable Business Analyst with a with a background in Compliance and Quality Assurance. Detail oriented and policy focused with seven years' experience in vendor/sourcing, compliance, and operational risk. Ability to manage data, analyze information to identify critical risks, to executive-level audiences. Experience working in Finance, HR and IT departments in large companies developing and implementing systems to improve data integrity and efficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Python| Solidity|Web3| Streamlit| Blockchain| Ethereum| Hashing| Archer| Threat Response| Ariba| Kronos Cognos| MS Excel| MS SharePoint| MS Visio| Crypto currency wallets |MS Word| MS Excel| MS SharePoint| Pandas Jupiter Notebook| SQL| Java| Tableau| Oracle| PeopleSoft| Workday| Vendor Risk Performance Management (VRPM SQL| Business Analysis| Business Requirements| SDLC | User Acceptance Testing| Agile| Waterfall| MySQL Requirements| Gathering| Test Cases| User Interface (UI)| Jira| Scrum | Service Now | Dynatrace | Venafi | Data Warehousing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

LPL Financial, Fort Mill, SC Jun 2022 – Present Business Analyst

- Key liaison between app developers and change management
- Responsible for managing and coordinating application SSL certificate renewals
- Work closely with key stakeholders to gather business requirements to create change records and coordinate the renewal process of SSL certificates.
- Responsible for ensuring changes to IT systems and applications are managed and implemented in accordance with the formal change management process
 - Perform User Acceptance Testing for certificate renewals
- Use data warehouse to store and analyze data on compliance issues and ensuring compliance regulations.
 - Analyzed data on client interactions and transactions.

Employment Gap Oct 2021 – Jun 2022

Took time off due to family responsibilities

United Mortgage Corp, Melville, NY Sep 2020 – Oct 2021 Business Analyst

• Requirements gathering and analysis and organization the requirements

according to their criticality.

- Key liaison for system engineers and client end users for user access and applicable UAT Testing.
 - Supported overall software development life cycle after implementation.
- Work closely with client and key stakeholders to ensure current and future business requirements are met.
- Created and issued email notifications to assigned project roles within JIRA for supported line of business.
- Collaborated with system engineers to validate/test code changes within applications.
 - Use of system and/or programs including Visio, Igrafx, JIRA, and SQL.
 - Stored and analyze data on compliance issues`

Walmart Global Shared Services, Charlotte, NC Jul 2016 – Sep 2020 Business Analyst II

- Key liaison between IT development and end users for implementation.
- Conducted requirement Gathering Sessions/Design sessions with the customer and internal team.
- Validated sourcing requests within Ariba approval flow to ensure compliance with company policy.
- Verified vendor information against all applicable Government agencies in effort to minimize risk.
- Generated and distributed metrics that provide data for future process improvements.
 - Managed emergency check payment queue within Accounts Payable.
- Responsible for driving process change to streamline enterprise shared services policies.
- Ensured successful and accurate vendor financial information maintained within Ariba database.
- Successfully implemented Ariba to 5,000 end users within Finance Department.
 - (Design, Configure, Test and Deploy)
- Collaborated with Internal Support Team during production migration of JIRA.
- Executed EFT, Wire disbursements to vendors on behalf of various departments within Ariba.

JZ&A Multi-Enterprise, York, SC May 2014 – Jul 2016 Operational Business Analyst

- Functioned as Business Analyst responsible for Requirements gathering and Analysis.
- Gathered and developed vendor management business requirements in accordance to line of business change requests.
- Responsible for leading Quarterly Business Review conference calls with vendors and senior level management.

- Identify potential compliance gaps within remediation efforts.
- Engaged in quality assurance activities to ensure vendors adhere to policies and SLA.
 - Validated and administered permission rights for SharePoint access.
- Ensured postproduction remediation activities adhere to business requirement documents.
- Worked with IT architects and other key stakeholders to ensure system architecture met business requirements.
 - Initiated performance improvement plans for vendors when needed.
- Coordinated with key stakeholders on disposition requirements and enforcement.
- Oversaw Vendor Risk Performance deliverables (VRPM) helping reduce risk and stay in compliance with bank policy.
- Responsible for validation and uploading vendor scorecards within internal proprietary system

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS:

• Associates Degree of Business Administration in Business Administration, York Technical College, 2009